我们已经介绍了使用ContentProvider进行查询
Now that we've covered querying
with our content provider,
现在可以开始插入数据了
it's time to start inserting data.
看一下我们在源代码中提供的
Let's take a look at the incomplete
content provider insert function
不完整的ContentProvider的insert函数
we provided in the source code.
正如你所看到的，这个函数利用了UriMatcher代码
As you can see, this function takes
advantage of the URI matcher code.
但它只需要基本的 URI
But it only requires the base URIs.
这是因为插入是从根本上简化的
That's because inserts
are fundamentally simpler.
我们只是想确保那些正确的记录会在正确的表格中结束
We simply want to make sure that the
right record ends up in the right table.
那些包含在其他URI中的数据，比如说 location和
The data that is contained in
the other URI, such as location and
date，实际上将会是在插入的数据中使用的值
date, will actually be in the content
values used in the insert.
请注意，如果我们想做的话，可以在这里支持所有的URI
Note that if we wanted to,
we could support all of the URIs here.
但它使得该插入函数的实现更加复杂
But it makes the implementation of the
insert function far more complicated.
当我们在数据库中插入数据的时候
When we insert into the database.
我们希望它可以将数据可能因为我们的插入而造成了改变了的消息
We wanted to notify every
content observer that might have
提醒所有的content observer
data modified by our insert.
事实证明，cursor通过注册自身通知其派生的后继
It turns out that cursors register
themselves as notify for descendents.
这意味着通知根URI也会同时通知所有的派生的URI
Which means that notifying the root
URI will also notify all descendents
即那些含有附加路径信息的URI
of the URI, ones that contain
additional path information.
比如说调用我们的ContentProvider
Just like with calling
our content providers.
我们可以使用ContentResolver去通知ContentObserver
We can use a content resolver
to notify our content observer.
正如你所见的，sunshine应用中每个表的根URI
As you can see, the root URI for
each table in sunshine
包含了上下文范围，规范和表名
just contains the context scope,
the authority, and the table name.
在这种情况下，包含日期的content URI
In the case presented,
the content URI that contains a date.
是天气content URI的派生
Is a descendant of the plain
weather content URI.
如果我们基于其他项目而不是根URI进行通知
If we notify based on anything
other than the root URI.
那么监听根URI的cursor就不能得到变化的通知
Then a cursor listening on the root
URI will not get notified of a change
而这肯定会对其造成影响
that would certainly impact it.
所以我们这样做的时候一定要十分谨慎
So we have to be very
careful when doing that.
让我们回到源代码中
Let's go back to the source code.
对于Weather来说，我们只需要把
For weather
we just passed the perimeters that came
这个参数传入到insert函数中就可以了
into the content provider into
the data base insert call.
插入失败的话，应该抛出一个异常
We should throw an exception
if the insert fails.
唯一的技巧就是保证返回一个正确的值
The only trick here is to make
sure we return the correct value.
在这里是一个URI
Which is a URI.
幸运的是我们已经写了一个建立URI的函数
Fortunately we made a function
to build these URIs
它通过ID来获取天气的路径
which contained the weather
path followed by an ID.
如果我们要保证ContentProvider完全的话
If we were being complete in our content
provider implementation, we should also
我们还应该在合约的UriMatcher和查询函数中提供这些URI类型
implement these URI types in the
contract URI matcher and query function.
但是实际上实现ContentProvider时有件不错的事是
But the beautiful thing about
implementing a content provider,
尤其是如果这些URI只被你的应用程序所使用的话
especially if it's only being
used by your application,
那你只需要去实现你所使用的功能就好了
is it you only need to
implement the features you use.
所以我们只是通过使用buildWeatherUri函数设置了return URI
So we just set the return URI by
using the build weather URI function.